http://www.manateememorial.com/privacy-policy

Skip Navigation
Privacy Policy
Home › Privacy Policy
Privacy StatementAt Manatee Memorial Hospital we respect the privacy of all our visitors. Please read our Online Privacy Policy carefully so that you understand our privacy practices relating to information we gather through this website.
Online Privacy Policy
You can view the policy in full, or select a specific privacy topic from the links below.
The Information We Collect
Protecting the Privacy of Children
Email Addresses
Devices and Browser Level Information
Pop-up Surveys
Information Collected by Third Parties
Security
Disclosure of Information
Retention of Information
Changes to this Privacy Policy
How to Contact Us
For questions about privacy, please contact 941-746-5111.
The Information We Collect
The information gathered by manateememorial.com generally falls into two categories: (1) information supplied by visitors to the site when they register or initiate transactions, and (2) tracking information gathered as visitors navigate through the site. Third-party providers, whose sites are featured on and accessed via our site, may gather information as well.
The information you provide helps us to respond to your expression of interest in employment. It also assists us in providing you with your requested physician referral, the programs and services available to those who sign up for Senior Advantage, and the conveniences associated with REGIE, our online pre-registration program. It also helps us respond to your questions or comments, and assist you with registration for classes and seminars.
If you submit an Application for Employment we require various demographic information including your name, address, telephone number; information about your work history, education, particular skills or training, honors and awards, and your professional licenses. We also ask for employment references, and your consent to various terms and conditions of employment.
If you complete our Senior Advantage Application form, we ask for personal information including your name, address, telephone number, age and date of birth. We may also ask for your Medicare Part A Claim numbers, and the identification of any supplemental insurance carrier. We discourage supplying us with your personal medical information on this form.
When you supply us with a Physician Referral Request, we ask for various personal information including your name, age, address, telephone number, e-mail address and gender. We ask whether you would like us to respond to your request by e-mail or phone, and we ask for an identification of your primary health insurance plan. Additionally we ask about your physician preferences for gender, specialty and qualifications. Lastly, we ask for the name of your family doctor, a description of your specific medical concerns, and whether or not you have previously seen a physician about your concerns.
When you elect to pre-register for hospital services by completing our REGIE online registration form, we ask for much of the same personal information requested during registration at the hospital: Name and primary language of the patient; name of person completing the registration form and his/her relationship to the patient; whether the patient has an advance directive or a durable power of attorney; an identification of the health care services requested; identification of the patient primary care, and admitting physicians; name and address of employer; diagnosis or the reasons for seeking treatment, a history of the patient's prior hospital admissions; name, address, telephone and social security number(s), occupation, and employer of person responsible for paying the bill; emergency contact information; and an identification of the primary and secondary insurance plans of the person responsible for paying the bill. In some cases we may ask for your name, address, city and state of residence, gender, and work and home phone numbers in order to register you for classes and seminars. In all cases where we invite you to submit questions or comments, we ask for your e-mail address.
Protecting the Privacy of Children
Manatee Memorial Hospital does not market to or employ children. Children should always get permission from their parents before sending any information about themselves (such as their names, email addresses and phone numbers) over the Internet, to us or to anyone else. If you're under 18, please don't provide any personally identifying information during your visit to manateememorial.com.
Email Addresses
If you provide us your email address, from time to time we may send you emails that we believe will interest you. We will not share your email address with providers of products or services. If you do not wish to receive email, please indicate when you give us your email address that you'd prefer not to receive such information. If you provide us with your e-mail address, we may also use your email address to answer any email you send us, or to follow up on your visit concerning registration, physician referrals or any of our classes or programs. Such follow-ups may include inquiries on transactions or submissions of information that appear incomplete.
Devices and Browser Level Information
We routinely log Non-PII that is automatically generated when all users visit or use the website and it’s services as a by-product of the user's activities. This information includes, but is not limited to HTTP header information, such as the browser being used at the time, the operating system being used at the time, and the URL of the webpage or other asset within the website that is being requested. This information is automatically passed between a user's device and analytics tools and may also include details relating to the activities users perform within the website, such as what links they click on, in what order they access specific web pages within the website and the search queries they perform.
In addition, our Web server automatically collects your IP address when you request pages from our server. An IP address is a number that is used by computers connected to the Internet to identify your computer so that data (such as the web pages you request) can be sent to you. Your IP address does not tell us who you are. We also collect information on the operating system you're running on your computer and the web browser software you're using to access our site so we can optimize our site for the most popular operating systems and web browsers.
We also use standard internet tools, such as third-party web Heat Maps, to help analyze where visitors go and what they do while visiting our website.
We do not connect any information we collect to our log files, analytics packages, or standard internet tools.
Pop-up Surveys
We may provide you the opportunity to participate in surveys. Participation in these surveys is completely voluntary. Your feedback will help us improve the website and other products and services. We do not collect any PII.
Information Collected by Third Parties
Our website may include links to other websites, and provide access to products and services offered by third parties, whose privacy policies we don't control. When you access another website or purchase products or services or conduct other transactions through our website, use of any information you provide is governed by the privacy policy of the operator of the site you're visiting or the provider of such products or services. The provider's privacy practices may differ from ours. If you can't find the privacy policy of any of our provider partners via a link either from the site's home page or from the pages on which the products or services are offered, you should contact the provider directly for more information.
Security
We use reasonable, appropriate and customary procedures or technologies to ensure the confidentiality of any personal information you send to us.
Generally, the information we collect from our visitors is stored in databases we control. Physical access to the servers on which we store visitor information is restricted. We don't share your personal information with anyone, except as may be necessary to verify your education, experience, and other qualifications for employment.
We use reasonable, appropriate and customary procedures or technologies to ensure the confidentiality of any personal information you send to us.
We make reasonable efforts to ensure that business partners’ websites to which we link, or with whom we share your information to provide services to you, employ security measures that meet our criteria and standards.
Some of the security measures we use include (but are not limited to):
Policies and procedures to ensure your information is only accessible to people who need the information and is used for the purposes intended.
Use of SSL encryption to securely transmit sensitive information between your computer and our website.
Use other strong military grade encryption methods to store and exchange data between systems and those authorized to use your information.
Use high-grade methods to destroy and dispose of your information when it is no longer needed.
Ensure that our systems are running up to date anti-virus software and the latest security updates are installed.
Please note that most Web browsers allow use of an SSL connection. If your browser does not support use of an SSL connection, or if you prefer not to send your personal information over the Internet, you can mail it to the appropriate address noted on this website.
Disclosure of Information
The personal information supplied by applicants for employment is shared selectively with individuals in the Human Resources Department of the hospital, and it may be shared as well with recruiting and hiring managers in our home office, and at our affiliated hospitals who have a business reason to know of the information because of their assigned duties.
Any personal information submitted on the form accessed through the link to "Contact" or "Contact Us", is sent directly to the appropriate department director, who may share it with departmental or other hospital personnel whose training or expertise is necessary to provide an answer to the inquiry.
Additionally, we may occasionally release information about visitors to our site when release is appropriate to comply with law, or to protect the rights, property or safety of visitors to our site, our customers, the public or Universal Health Services. As our business grows, we may buy or sell various assets. In the unlikely event that Universal Health Services, one of its affiliated units, or substantially all of its assets are acquired by another company, information about our visitors would be among the transferred assets.
Retention of Information
The information submitted through this site is retained in accordance with state and/or and federal laws, and document retention policies of this hospital and/or its parent company.
Changes to This Privacy Policy
This privacy policy is subject to change. The Web is an evolving medium. If we need to change our privacy policy at some point in the future, we'll post the new policy promptly. If at any point we decide to use personally identifiable information in a manner different from what was stated at the time it was collected, we will notify you and give you an opportunity to opt out of the proposed use. By using manateememorial.com you agree that your visit to our site, and any dispute over privacy, is governed by the then-current version of the Online Privacy Policy.
Questions or Complaints
If you have any questions or complaints that concern this Online Privacy Policy, please contact the Privacy Officer at the facility. The representative will respond to your inquiries or help resolve any dispute concerning this Online Privacy Policy.
Effective date: August 25, 2017.
